Unitarian Universalist Association. "Carnes for UUA President" Campaign. Records, 1975-1979 (bMS 394): A Finding Aid.
Unitarian Universalist Association. "Carnes for UUA President" Campaign. Records, 1975-1979.
Andover-Harvard Theological Library, Harvard Divinity School
bMS 394
Unitarian Universalist Association.
7 boxes
Records of Paul Carnes' UUA presidential campaign, including correspondence, general campaign material, and treasurer's records. The papers span 1975-1979.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Peter Spilman Raible, 1980.
Access
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Paul Nathaniel Carnes (1921-1979) earned an AB from Indiana University in 1942. He then enlisted in the U.S. Army, and on Christmas Day, 1942, he was captured by German forces in North Africa and spent the duration of the war as a German P.O.W. Following World War II, he enrolled in Harvard Divinity School, where he earned an STB in 1948. He served Unitarian parishes in Ohio, Tennessee, and New York, and served as president of the Unitarian Universalist Association from 1977 to 1979. He is the author of For Freedom and Belief: A Manual for Unitarians (1952) and Longing of the Heart: Prayers and Invocations (1979).
Organized into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Campaign material
Series II. Treasurer's records
This collection consists of material related to Carnes' UUA presidential campaign. It includes correspondence, mainly as it relates to the Carnes campaign, and is arranged chronologicallyl; campaign material that includes literature, publicity, and photographs related to the campaign; and treasurer's records that include correspondence, lists of supporters and contributions, and files on the other candidates.
Related Materials
For related collections, please see bMS 533.
- The number after the slash in each entry in the following list indicates the box number, and the number in parentheses is the folder number.
- Information about the gift, 1980, bMS 394/1 (1)
- Carnes Advisory Committee. Records of meetings, June 1975-June 1976 (note: the committee did not always have this name), bMS 394/1 (2)
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence of the people involved in the Carnes campaign, April-June 1975, bMS 394/1 (3)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, July 1975, bMS 394/1 (4)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, August 1975, bMS 394/1 (5)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, September 1975, bMS 394/1 (6)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, October 1975, bMS 394/1 (7)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, November 1975, bMS 394/1 (8)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, December 1975, bMS 394/1 (9)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, January 1976, bMS 394/1 (10)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, February 1976, bMS 394/1 (11)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, March 1976, bMS 394/1 (12)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, April 1976, bMS 394/1 (13)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, May 1976, bMS 394/1 (14)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, June 1976, bMS 394/2 (1 )
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, July 1976, bMS 394/2 (2 )
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, August 1976, bMS 394/2 (3 )
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, September 1976, bMS 394/2 (4 )
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, October 1976, bMS 394/2 (5 )
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, November 1976, bMS 394/2 (6 )
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, December 1976, bMS 394/2 (7 )
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, January 1977, bMS 394/2 (8 )
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, February 1977, bMS 394/2 (9 )
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, March 1-15, 1977, bMS 394/3 (1)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, March 16-31, 1977, bMS 394/3 (2)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, April 1-15, 1977, bMS 394/3 (3)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, April 16-30, 1977, bMS 394/3 (4)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, May 1977, bMS 394/3 (5)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, June 1977, bMS 394/3 (6)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, July 1977, bMS 394/3 (7)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, August 1977, bMS 394/3 (8)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, September 1977, bMS 394/3 (9)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, October 1977, bMS 394/3 (10)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, November 1977, bMS 394/3 (11)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, February 1978, bMS 394/3 (12)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, May 1978, bMS 394/3 (13)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, June 1978, bMS 394/3 (14)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, September 1978, bMS 394/3 (15)
  - Correspondence, Carnes campaign, September 1979, bMS 394/3 (16)
- Series II. Campaign material
  - Carnes petitions for nomination for president of the UUA, bMS 394/4 (1)
  - Correspondence relating to the petitions, March 1976-June 1976, bMS 394/4 (2)
  - General Assembly, 1976, bMS 394/4 (3)
  - General Assembly, 1977, bMS 394/4 (4)
  - Carnes campaign organization, material relating to how churches might vote, bMS 394/4 (5-6)
  - Carnes campaign organization, list of names, bMS 394/4 (7)
  - List of persons supporting Carnes, bMS 394/4 (8)
  - Carnes campaign material, bMS 394/4 (9)
  - Carnes campaign: literature and publicity, bMS 394/5 (1-4)
  - "Carnes Carrousel": a campaign publication issued June 1976-June 1977, bMS 394/5 (5)
  - Plan book of engagements, etc. for the campaign, September 1976-June 1977, bMS 394/5 (6)
  - Carnes campaign memorabilia, bMS 394/5 (7)
  - Photograph of Carnes, bMS 394/5 (8)
  - Carnes miscellaneous material, bMS 394/5 (9)
- Series III. Treasurer's records
  - Treasurer's records and correspondence, bMS 394/6 (1-2)
  - List of groups giving money, bMS 394/6 (3)
  - Checking deposits, November 1976-September 1977, bMS 394/6 (4)
  - Cancelled checks, #1-154, June 1975-July 1979, bMS 394/6 (5)
  - List of supporters and contributions: A-C, bMS 394/6 (6)
  - List of supporters and contributions: D-G, bMS 394/6 (7)
  - List of supporters and contributions: H-K, bMS 394/6 (8)
  - List of supporters and contributions: L-O, bMS 394/7 (1)
  - List of supporters and contributions: P-S, bMS 394/7 (2)
  - List of supporters and contributions: T-Z, bMS 394/7 (3)
  - People listed as undeclared or supporting another candidate, bMS 394/7 (4)
  - Carnes campaign file on other candidates, bMS 394/7 (5-6)